<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BASH Lab</title>
    <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BASH Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Bashima, 2021 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We are looking for highly motivated students to join BASH lab. Please contact us if you want to work on machine learning and computation on trillions of sustainable IoT devices.</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/post/vacancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/post/vacancy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BreathTrack: Detecting Regular Breathing Phases from Unannotated Acoustic Data Captured by a Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/breathtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/breathtrack/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Development of a Child through AI and Mobile Sensing</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/littlebeats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/littlebeats/</guid>
      <description>We are developing an affordable and comfortable new mobile sensing device (called LittleBeats™) that children between age 3 to 24 months will wear in the home. LittleBeats™ is equipped with sensors to measure motion and heart rate, as well as a microphone to record audio. Designed with a small and sleek shape, the device easily fits inside of a specially designed shirt pocket. It is attached by placing three hypoallergenic gel stickers on your child’s skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bashima Islam</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/users.wpi.edu/~bislam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/users.wpi.edu/~bislam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bashima Islam</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/users.wpi.edu/~bislam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/users.wpi.edu/~bislam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zygarde: Time-Sensitive On-Device Deep Inference and Adaptationon Intermittently-Powered Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/zygarde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/zygarde/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Intermittent Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/intermittent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/intermittent/</guid>
      <description>Current development of extremely low-power computing devices and efficient energy harvesters led to the creation of computing systems that are powered by intermittently available harvested energy, e.g., solar, piezoelectric, and radio-frequency (RF). Such computing systems go through power-on and off phases due to the lack of adequate harvesting energy. These systems are known as Intermittent Computing Systems. While existing works on intermittent computing systems concentrate preliminary on the lower level goals, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BreathEasy: Assessing Respiratory Diseases Using Mobile Multimodal Sensors</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/breatheasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/breatheasy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Time Synchronization of Multimodal Cough Events from Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/cough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/cough/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling Computational and Energy Harvesting Tasks in Deadline-Aware Intermittent Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/celebi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/celebi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Forum Abstract: Scheduling Tasks on Intermittently Powered Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/phd_forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/phd_forum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in Reliability and Predictability of Harvested Energy from Battery-less Intermittently Powered Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/harvester/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/harvester/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Chargers will Make Mobile Devices Live Longer</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/battery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/battery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermittent Learning: On-Device Machine Learning on Intermittently Powered System</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/learning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Abstract: On-Device Training from Sensor Data on Batteryless Platforms</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/energy_poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/energy_poster/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time-Aware Deep Intelligence on Batteryless Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/wip-zygarde/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/wip-zygarde/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Pedestrian Safety in Cities using Intelligent Wearable Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/pawsj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/pawsj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRaIn: Making a Case for LoRa in Indoor Localization</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/lorain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/lorain/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Neural Sensing for Mobile Health and Safety</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/audio/</guid>
      <description>Breathing biomarkers, such as breathing rate, fractional inspiratory time, and inhalation-exhalation ratio, are vital for monitoring the user&amp;rsquo;s health and well-being. We assesses the potential of using smartphone acoustic sensors for passive unguided breathing phase monitoring in a natural environment. We address the annotation challenges by developing a novel variant of the teacher-student deep neural network training method for transferring knowledge from an inertial sensor to an acoustic sensor, eliminating the need for manual breathing sound annotation by fusing signal processing with deep learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy-Efficient Computer Vision on Embedded Systems</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/vision/</guid>
      <description>Camera is the one of the most usable and common sensors in the current world. With the development of low-power camera and highly efficient embedded processors computer vision is now available in our daily handheld devices including smartphones. In this research, we explore the different computer vision applications, e.g., 3D reconstruction, augmented reality, and provide more energy-efficient solutions by controlling the image acquisition and image processing stages and intergrating other modalities, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localization using Low Power Network</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/localization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/project/localization/</guid>
      <description>Mobility tracking of internet of things (IoT) devices in smart city infrastructures such as smart buildings, hospitals, shopping centers, warehouses, smart streets, and outdoor spaces has many applications, and BLE is available in almost every IoT device in the market nowadays. Developing an accurate ranging technique for Low powered network-enabled, e.g., Lora, BLE, IoT devices (both battery powered and batterless) is a challenging feat as billions of these devices are already in use, and for pragmatic reasons, we cannot propose to modify the IoT device (a BLE peripheral) itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glimpse.3D: A Motion-Triggered Stereo Body Camera for 3D Experience Capture and Preview</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/glimpse3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/glimpse3d/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Ranging of Unmodified BLE Peripherals in Smart City Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/bleloc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/bleloc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Abstract: SEUS: A Wearable Multi-Channel Acoustic Headset Platform to Improve Pedestrian Safety</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/seus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/seus/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duty-Cycle-Aware Real-Time Scheduling of Wireless Links in Low Power WANs</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/duty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/duty/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance Approximate Computing by Adaptive Relaxed Synchronization</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/hpcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/hpcc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARBLE: Mobile Augmented Reality Using a Distributed BLE Beacon Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/marble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/marble/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paws: A Wearable Acoustic System for Pedestrian Safety</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/paws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/paws/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoundSifter: Mitigating Overhearing of Continuous Listening Devices</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/soundsifter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/soundsifter/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventive Maintenance of Centralized HVAC Systems: Use of Acoustic Sensors, Feature Extraction, and Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/hvac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 16:37:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/publication/hvac/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Member 3</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/collaborators/member3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/collaborators/member3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Member 3</title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/member/member3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/member/member3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/about/</guid>
      <description>Sed extemplo conantur et Cnosia harundine lyra Agros metitur venatibus catenis quippe honorem tuorum Lorem markdownum finemque prunaque longe et sunt. Sed super aulaea in Paridis noctisque cubile? Iacit coetus, vastatoremque dedit; Vidi magna, recurvatis copia. Quod sit; per cingo tamen Hyperionis si vacat inclitus instabat curaque arma saxea, naturaeque pondere quaeque aer!
 Agros apertum aliis dominaeque rapidus Prima nulla est Hortatibus voto  Anum istis praefertur est Quaque coeptis lumina mea nuda dentes semine agitavit, caesique voluptas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/approach/</guid>
      <description>Et malis vellet tellus deseruere in credant Inde sidera moenia lacertis nomen nostra membra Lorem markdownum miranti. Sonus faciunt omnibus frustra: illa possem ad regio Anubis tamen. Sustulerat debent fluviis herbis attollere rogus et formae nitentem avellere motis clipeus Achilles felix videam undas. Posuit haec ipse posse.
Ore fame mons Olympi tantae stringit columbas proxima habebat, longius alta non. Haeserat gerunt detinuit genis est huc, dixit tam dumque nitidum.
 Cristata causam Triones moenia habentem subito utentem Astraea castris contentus nisi leve eum invia Inferiusque capta cognoscenda flaventi locuta notavi fallere Moriens scripsi ictus tuo cum  Tarpeias insurgens summo sinistra vertice, in neve utroque exempla Cyparissus tanta tecti terras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/mission/</guid>
      <description>Auras queritur facientes dixit venti sustinui E in mora Lorem markdownum poenaque nuper destituit silendo quoniam, nec ait consorte membra, figuram hanc cum. Manifesta vitae facies exiguumque iunctam dictis. Vidit eadem, hanc cum descendit sinu misit quem fecit, positisque pastorve. Missus solos potentia in erant noctem est!
if (dvdProcessorVolume &amp;lt; mpegProcess(slashdot, gigahertz)) { transferAnsiBotnet.and(logSoftware, hsfClipboardSubnet.queue_publishing( systemMemory, 5, yahoo)); } else { swappableIpv -= spoolingAdwareCrossplatform; extranetAppArchitecture(1, dtd_rpc_font(45, 67, development_sli)); } antivirus_ipv = touchscreenFiosGrep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/research/</guid>
      <description>Modo est Non sub haedum tenet Lorem markdownum esse diversa quoque vocavit, quam! Vires tibi axis dum spolium vaticinor fulminis, a dixere attrahit generisque tamen?
 Petit invergens iram praetendat iam Mecum res curva iunctura silvis hoc leonum Iacent gemitum quos  Non est duram mitis sonat proculcat tumulos Alce bimembres Dauni, cur ex voces referam adunco in sors. Manibusque poples prodidit lata tantum quem suos ratae Aeginae sederunt degenerat Bacchus descendere, patriisque ieiunia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/vacancy/vacancy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://users.wpi.edu/~bislam/bashlab/vacancy/vacancy1/</guid>
      <description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.
Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
